(+44)7864612363 London, United Kingdom ojorgensen1417@gmail.com

Ole Jorgensen

AI MSc Student @ Imperial

Website: ojorgensen.github.io LinkedIn: ole-jorgensen

Studying for a MSc in Artificial Intelligence at Imperial College London.

Graduated with an MMath from St Andrews, one of the top 50 academically performing students across all 2022 graduates at the University.

I have twice led successful research projects in Pure Mathematics, and have a lot of experience in leadership roles. Confident programming in Python.

EXPERIENCE

Researcher

Jul 2021 — September 2021

University of St Andrews

- Undertook original research in Pure Mathematics alongside Prof. Colin Bleak and two other undergraduates, wherein we investigated rotation and conjugacy in Thompson's Group T.
- Found novel conditions that candidate solutions must satisfy to describing rotation as a commutator.
- Funding provided by the Maths Department's Summer Internship Programme.

Researcher Jun 2020 — Aug 2020

University of St Andrews

- Completed original research in Pure Mathematics on the Rado Complex under the supervision of Prof. Peter Cameron, with funding from the Laidlaw Foundation.
- Explanatory paper and poster published on the Laidlaw Scholar's Network.

Co-President May 2020 — May 2022

Effective Altruism St Andrews

- Designed and ran an introductory mentorship programme for new members (SPEAK), more than doubling applications year on vear.
- Coordinated a committee to run successful Speaker Events, Career Workshops, and Discussion Groups.
- Successfully obtained several grants totalling over £5000 from the EA Infrastructure Fund to support the group

Volunteer May 2021 — Jul 2021

Open Cages

- Worked full time during the Summer with funding from the Laidlaw Foundation.
- Conducted independent research on the international broiler market, informing the charity's big-picture strategy on which markets to target in order to maximise impact.
- Directly collaborated with the CEO to run a successful fundraising campaign, writing emails to tens of thousands of supporters.

Club Captain Mar 2020 — Mar 2022

St Andrews Shinty Club

- Coordinated 3x training sessions a week throughout the academic year, managed the team during games and tournaments.
- Adapted all sessions to adhere to constantly changing COVID-19 restrictions throughout the pandemic, restructuring training sessions and establishing track and trace systems.

EDUCATION

MSc Artificial Intelligence 2022 - 2023

Imperial College London

- First term modules: Python Programming, Reinforcement Learning, Introduction to Machine Learning, Mathematics for Machine Learning, and Introduction to Symbolic AI
- Planned second term modules: Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Probabilistic Inference, Computational Optimisation, and AI Software Engineering Group Project
- · Attending the Imperial AI Safety Reading Group

MMath (Hons) Mathematics 2018 – 2022

University of St Andrews

- Module Average 19.1/20, equivalent to 4.0 GPA.
- Modules Including Measure and Probability Theory, Discrete Geometry, Galois Theory, and Symbolic Computation.
- My Dissertation successfully generalised several results regarding homogeneous graphs in the context of homogeneous k-hypergraphs.

A Levels 2016 — 2018

Highworth Grammar School

• A*, A*, A*, A in Maths, Further Maths, Physics and English Literature

(+44)7864612363 London, United Kingdom ojorgensen1417@gmail.com

Ole Jorgensen

AI MSc Student @ Imperial

Website: ojorgensen.github.io LinkedIn: ole-jorgensen

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Laidlaw Scholarship 2020 – 2021

Received the Laidlaw Research and Leadership Scholarship, a competitive programme from the Laidlaw Foundation.

Funded my work with Prof. Peter Cameron and Open Cages.

The Principal's Scholarship for Academic Excellence

2022

Award presented to each of the top 50 academically performing students in their final year of study at the University of St Andrews.

Senior Honours Project Commendation

2022

My dissertation "Generalising Homogeneous Structures" was highly commended by assessors.

Duncan Prize (Applied Mathematics)

2019

Awarded to the best student of Applied Mathematics at Second Level.

Dean's List

2019, 2020, 2021, 2022

Awarded for obtaining an average of 16.5 or higher (a 1st) for the academic year.